[Music]
w
hello and welcome back episode 202 of
the asket show is live and I am so glad
to be back with you on this live stream
I can see there's a lot of people
waiting and and commenting so so let me
see who all is there before I do that
let me uh inform you that this is a
comments based live stream which means
that I'm going to take questions that
you have asked in the comments I'm going
to do a bunch of those and then if
there's time I'll take a bunch of com
questions from the live chat as well but
first from the comments so let's see who
all is there on the live stream I can
see Shiva Mahajan gorov Sharma genis
Naidu wkar Z J sankit ganor rajbir Singh
J chitri Charan h hello Anonymous aush
Pand K omik hello niharika Gupta hello
patil hello Raa ainash suit
statement online hello Nan rhan rut
majar ABI Gad Vice person Nomad Ron
threeways S2 Tushar Gupta aramana
rakshit Vishnu U gorav Sharma ragir
solanki s ganor Vu Zub is hello Hindi
status VD Sam Rashmi Rea Singh FR Ripper
hardik
baroa Ys
smfx uh three ways S2 utar sanket
geopolitical dub ewad Fe rajbir Singh XM
Yus Z wise person brul chaitan shiv
Abdullah Anand Chandra Karan KV paidar
epic tias bavya Rod mahes Sharma Dr J
Shankar hello bkash Kumar aush Pand Nita
kumavat viandi Mar Panda bishal Dash
Kenneth tan from the Philippines hello
thank you so much uh threeways S2
Priyanka jaala uh about tech McLovin
hello
kikan om prakash and everybody else
Vladimir
CH uh okay I'm going to stop
uh greeting everybody otherwise we'll
never start di SJ s hello okay let's
take some questions from the comments so
let's see what questions we've had a lot
of questions as well and I've been able
to take only a few and I apologize in
advance to those of you whose questions
I was not able to take but here we go
let's take
questions anit Gupta says you need to do
at least three hour podcast a lot has
happened in the last three weeks where
is sh Jinping venkadesh says uh is sh
Jinping dead there's a lot of news
coming from there about and corruption
in the Chinese Army so I'm hearing this
chatter on social media that xinping is
apparently dead I've heard no news
source saying that I've not heard this
in in any news report seems to be rumors
swirling around and chatter on social
media I'm not sure what the source of
this news is or this rumor is I'm not
sure what the origin is I have seen
absolutely nothing that makes me believe
that there is something wrong with SH
Jinping maybe he's dead or something uh
I I hear news that he has released some
statement about congratulating uh
somebody in Vietnam about some somebody
ascending to some uh to the chief chief
hood of the Vietnamese Communist party
or something like that so there seems to
be activity when it comes to Mr shanping
I'm not sure who has started this rumor
or what it is but I have seen nothing
that corroborates this and I remember
it's this this sort of thing comes out
from time to time I think it was last
year or the year before that that there
was this news all over social media even
big channels carried it that apparently
there's been a coup in China and Mr shij
Jinping has been deposed and I actually
said at the time that Mr shenping is
actually consolidating his power at the
time and it turned out that I was right
so right now I think I have seen no
evidence that points in the direction of
something having happened to Mr sh
Jinping so uh yeah I would not take it
that serious but let's let's wait and
watch I'm sure we will get some kind of
news out of China soon enough so I don't
think there's anything that's happened
to Mr CH from whatever I have seen thus
far Corruption of the Chinese Army well
there's corruption in China there's
corruption in every nation the US is the
most corrupt nation in the world China
obviously is a large Nation there's
going to be some corruption at some
levels Mr shining has been cracking down
on corruption the Chinese Communist
party is known to have corruption and
there are very harsh penalties for
corrupt corruption in China essentially
you get shot or you know you get
executed for being for being caught uh
indulging in corruption so it's very
harsh over there as it should be
actually and that's just the way it is
okay next
question travel with swap says why did
President Joe Biden step down for the
2024 election so he has Mr Biden or
whoever is managing his account has uh
well announced that Mr Biden will not be
uh a candidate presidential candidate in
the upcoming presidential election in
the US and they have appointed Miss
Kamala Harris the current vice president
as the Democratic party's nominee for
the president of the US so it's going to
be Miss Kamala Harris versus Mr Trump
that's what the election is going to be
like so why did Mr Joe Biden step down
well I think the reasons are obvious the
guy is clearly in well irreparable
cognitive decline he's way too old
sometimes well he's even his height
seems to change sometimes it's 6 feet
whatever one Ines or whatever whatever
his height is and sometimes 65 what on
Earth is that sometimes he looks younger
sometimes he looks older and as it is he
was not doing well mentally he would
shake hands with people who would try to
shake hands with people that Wen there
on stage and he always looks confused
and disoriented so it's it's no surprise
that the guy or whoever is managing his
accounts has announced that he is
stepping down he will not be contesting
the election and he has apparently uh
endorsed Kamala Harris's candidature for
the US president's role and uh people
have been saying that it was a well she
was in a rally and there was a message
from Joe Biden apparently live but it
looked like it was a AI generated
message so there all kinds of I don't
know questions being raised about Joe
Biden you know people are saying there's
a there are body doubles of Joe Biden
there are play acting instead of him
maybe he's somewhere in some institution
somewhere or or who knows what so it's
it's clear that if the guy runs for
election is going to lose okay no matter
what they do with the with the votes is
goingon to lose because no one can vote
for a guy like that a guy who is way
past his expiry date
so that's why Kamala is now going to run
as the Democratic uh candidate and what
should actually happen as part of the
procedure in the US is that each party
uh has what's called a round of
primaries okay which is an internal
election and you you have debates
between all the candidates from the
Republican party and the Democratic
party for who's going to be the the
official candidate from the party so
let's say from the Democratic party
there's going to be like five or six or
seven or 10 people who want to be the
presidential candidate from from that
party so they're going to have debates
Etc live debates tele televised debates
and then there's going to be voting in
all the states and then the nominee will
be elected so that's how it generally
happens but in this case it's they've
just selected this lady Kamala Harris
undemocratically I would say but that's
the nature of uh uh politics in the US
it's not really a democracy it's an
autocracy masquerading is a democracy so
no big surprise there so that's the
situation in the US when it comes to the
Democratic party's nominee uh for the
upcoming presidential
election okay a couple of questions
about Mr Trump rajit Chopra says was
Trump's assassination attempt
pre-planned will this event influence
the upcoming presidential elections in
the US and Sonia says do you think that
is a chance for Trump to win this year's
election after the assassination attempt
and the ongoing anti-trump campaigns
look uh there's going to be ongoing
campaigns against him it's going to be
orchestrated and paid for by the
Democrats which is normal the par is
oppose each other and they want their
candidate to win so that's
normal uh so that's the there is that
now was the Trump assassination attempt
pre-planned well obviously there is some
premeditation that go goes behind this
even if even if you assume that the guy
the the Assassin was acting alone on his
own well he would have gone and
purchased arms the the weapon the
ammunition he would have scouted out the
area where the uh rally was going to be
held he would have found the best
location from which you can take a clear
shot at the um at Mr Trump he put a
ladder there or somebody put a ladder
there and then he climbs up on the roof
of the thing he lies there for at least
an hour in wait and then it takes the
shot or multiple shots uh so clearly
there was planning in behind this
obviously it was the best possible
location from where you can take a shot
for from where anyone could have taken a
shot at Mr Trump and to to security
Personnel it was the glaringly obvious
place from which any potential
assassination attempt would happen and
that's the daily job of the Secret
Service in the US to look out for these
things and they completely failed at
that so it looks
like there's more to this than catches
our eye and U the US has had a history
of such things you know uh President
Kennedy was taken out in Dallas in
1963 then later later on when his
younger brother Robert F Kennedy tried
to he was a presidential candidate he
was also taken out and yeah that was
very tragic
Etc so these things are known to happen
in the
US uh so yeah that's what I can say
about that it's something is very murky
in here something's very fishy will this
event influence the upcoming US
presidential elections clearly there's
going to be uh an impact of this in the
elections in the election assuming Mr
Trump survives that there's no more
attempts on his life and he's the
election actually goes goes ahead then
clearly there's going to be some
signific impact of this on the election
lots of people have come out in the open
after this attempt in in the support for
Mr Trump for example Elon Musk has
publicly endorsed Mr Trump's candidature
other people Hulk Hogan the the wrestler
and many other people have now come out
in the open and Endor Mr Trump so
there's been a significant change in in
the climate the political climate in the
US in the past it was kind of you know
people were uh were reluctant to express
or verbalize or come out with the you
know an an openly Express their support
from Mr Trump because it was SE to be
something that was kind of taboo or
verboten that uh you know orange man bad
that sort of thing but now people are
coming out in support of Mr Trump so if
the election is a free and fair election
it's highly likely that Mr Trump will be
reelected as US president but well
you never know what happens in the US
okay 2020 people lots of people say was
a stolen election a rigged election and
it's possible that 24 also could go that
way uh so I think it's quite likely that
Miss Kamala Harris will become the US
president uh the entire establishment is
against Mr Trump and Mr Trump has said
that he he wants to uh drain the swamp
and reform the system etc etc etc which
obviously the the people who are in
power will obviously not like that they
because it will affect them it will
impact them directly so yeah so it's
unlikely in my opinion that Mr Trump
wins and if he wins then well let's see
how long he lasts unless he has made a
deal with the
devil well you never know yeah okay
next Ramesh Karne says Mr Modi visited
Mr puin and now the news is that they
that Mr Modi will meet zalinsky as well
is this because of pressure from the US
okay good question so Mr Modi did
recently visit Russia and he met with
President Putin uh so we have restarted
resumed the annual Summit that happens
between the between the two Nations
India and Russia and it was important it
was an important meeting uh it was an
important event for India as well as for
Russia Russia the entire world kind of
especially the Western world and the
Western influenced world
is kind of anti-russia right now you
will find lots of people in India
believeing expressing the opinion that
Russia is at fault Vis A what's happened
in Ukraine the Russian special military
operation so to say in Ukraine Russia is
the aggressor lots of people believe
that this is Russia's war on Ukraine Etc
Russia is the aggressor Russia is
expansionist Nation all
that uh so there is that but Russia the
the relation so Russia essentially to a
large extent especially in the media and
in public opinion is kind of an isolated
Nation from that perspective if you look
at the Olympics that are ongoing Russian
athletes aren't allowed to compete under
the Russian flag to compete under some
random what the Olympic flag or
something uh and so on so that's the
deal so it is important for Russia to to
prioritize its ties it its relations
with with Nations like IND which are
friendly nations with which Russia has
significant convergence of national
interests and it's also important for
Russia to India is especially important
for Russia because Russia otherwise uh
it's it's in danger of becoming
completely dependent on China so hosting
Mr Modi was great for Mr Putin it allows
him to tell the West that you know India
isn't your creature India isn't beholden
to you India will do what it wants and
India is a good friend of ours we have a
excellent relationship with India it
also is well it also enables Mr Putin to
send a message to China then you know we
have options you're not the only one and
so on so it was it's it's very important
for Russia for India also it's important
because we have a significant
convergence of interests with Russia uh
the West isn't entirely friendly to
India the West doesn't want India to
grow the way it should grow okay there's
a lot that's happening Visa the W in
India which means the US and India
there's a lot of pressure that the US is
putting on India the US is doing much
that is well harmful to India in order
to
to to prevent India's growth and to to
arrest India's accelerating or or growth
economic growth Etc and geopolitical
Rise as well in the region there's a lot
that's happening so
India also needs needs to send messages
to the US that we have options as well
we have an excellent relationship with
the nation that you fear the most Russia
because the US fears Russia the most so
overall it was great it was very
important this that this relationship
continues and the annual Summits resume
so there was there was that and now the
news has come that Mr Modi is going to
visit he's going to meet with Mr
delinski so is this because of us
pressure probably to some EXT years so
the us obviously the West Was extremely
unhappy with the Mr Mod's visit to the
US and they criticized it a lot in there
were lots of oped written about that
lots of articles in in the US and and
British and Western media and so on lots
of disparaging comments from various
esteemed and emminent commentators
Etc uh so in order to kind of balance
things out because India also has a well
we also have a good working relationship
an important working relationship with
the West so Mr Modi probably because of
that has decided to meet with Mr Zin as
well what's the harm in meeting the guy
we all know he's a puppet he's a western
puppet he doesn't have any genuine power
as such he's just uh one of the
manifestations of Western interests so
meet with the guy have a meeting discuss
whatever should be discussed Etc talk
about peace and so on and that's about
it so yeah so that's the deal and
obviously there's going to there must
have been a lot of us pressure on India
and to kind of alleviate that we'll meet
with Mr Mr
zilinski CH the light says is World War
I inevitable look nothing is inevitable
but let's take a look at the world map
and see what are the big flash points
currently that we can think of right now
so as always we will open the map I hear
lots of people are using Maps these days
but anyway that's good I'm glad that's
happening so what are the big flash
points when we first of all let us
Define okay before we even go to the map
let's ask ourselves what do we mean by
World War I is a hypothetical future
India Pakistan war is that something we
would call world War I I would say no is
a
hypothetical future India China war
something that we would call World War I
I'd say no but what about Israel and
Iran going to war if that ever happens
hypothetically we don't want that to
happen but hypothetically if there's an
Israel Iran War is that World War I I'd
say no what if hypothetically there's a
war between China and Japan and let's
say even South Korea gets involved is
that World War I I would say no what if
there's a hypothetical future China us
war is that World War I I would say we
could be close to World War II in that
situation but it's still not World War I
so what is World War I is the question
well first of all World War I is a war
that will involve nuclear weapons
unfortunately we never want that to
happen but my definition of World War I
is first of all it's a cataclysmic war
that involves nuclear weapons and
secondly it has to involve the US and
Russia if it's just the US and China
fighting each other it's not World War I
it has to be the world's two most
powerful Nations which means the nations
with the largest nuclear arsenals and
Russia has more nuclear warheads than
the US Russia is the world's largest
nuclear
power so World War I necessarily
necessarily involves Warfare between
these two Powers the US which which is a
superpower which is the only superpower
in Russia which is a near
superpower so that's World War II a war
between the US and Russia and
unfortunately nuclear exchange which
obviously will obliterate the world the
Earth so is that
inevitable so what would it take for the
US and Russia to go to
war obviously it will not start with
Russia lobbing nuclear weapons of the US
or the US lobbing weapons you know
missiles or whatever in Russia it
probably will start somewhere else and
then there's a escalation chain that's
an escalation ladder that gets ramped up
and that's what happens so it could
start with a China thawan conflict
perhaps or it could start with something
that goes wrong in in West Asia the
Middle East it could start somewhere and
then things escalate it could even even
even the Ukraine situation could
escalate into a potential World War II
situation so let's take a look at the
potential Clash
points so um India Pakistan if there's a
war between these two Nations it will
not last very long unless the Chinese
get involved in which case the Americans
may get involved okay if they want to
but I don't see Russia getting involved
in this matter if if such a hypothetical
future War ever
happens so India Pakistan is not a World
War III
flasho what about India China if India
and China go to war the US may get
involved and then there could be a China
us conflict BL say but in that case
Russia could potentially get involved to
some
extent but not really so I don't see
even that escalating into World War I
what about the thawan situation China
Taiwan if China makes a move on Taiwan
well what could happen is what will
happen is that Taiwan will be
obliterated nothing will be left and
China will get a hollow Victory if China
actually succeeds in taking Taiwan most
likely they may not succeed in taking
Taiwan but does this escalate into World
War II well if China makes a move on
Taiwan the Americans will will
operationalize their military bases in
South Korea and Japan and Guam Etc that
could escalate into a proper fulls scale
full-blown us China
conflict but once again there's no need
Russia from its perspective will see no
need to get involved in that the Chinese
may ask for aid from Russia but why
would the Russians imperil their own
nation in such a war they could help
China with material Etc uh natural
resources weapons Etc but they may not
get involved directly so where could
World War II start well right now there
Middle East Iran uh Israel well I don't
see a us Russia military exchange coming
out of that unless Syria is involved and
we know that the Russians have uh
military Assets in Syria they have uh so
Latakia is is a place where the Russians
have uh a port Latakia
Port so the Russians use this port and
there's uh an Air Force Base also
somewhere nearby the Russians use and
that's how they have been able to
stabilize Syria and prevent the
government of Syria from falling because
the Americans tried to take out the
Syrian government in the
2010s that's how the entire Isis angle
came into play Etc but the Russians have
been able to prevent the Americans from
affecting regime change in Syria so
Syria Iraq Etc you could see some
potential us Russia US versus Russia
action maybe proxy action Etc but once
again it doesn't escalate into World War
I so right now as of today the only
place where you could have an escalation
is probably Ukraine if us soldiers or
NATO soldiers put their boots on the
ground in Ukraine and there are direct
Russia versus Nato clashes in that case
you could see an
escalation and yeah so right now it
looks like Ukraine is the only place
where such a thing could happen so my
main point is that US versus China if
there's a war that is not World War I
World War I is only if the US and Russia
go directly to war that is World War 3
and then there's a chain reaction and
unfortunately nukes if they ever get
used it obliterates the planet
so one hopes these scenarios never play
out one hopes this these things never
happen so in my opinion World War II is
definitely not inevitable we don't want
that to happen and hopefully sane Minds
Prevail
okay okay a bunch of questions about uh
Han ronak Mel says why did irgc Kill Han
Iranian revolutionary Gods cor really is
that what you're saying is what you're
alleging the second question is by Sam
Satish the Arabs have kept quiet of the
assassination of the Hamas Chief Mr is
KH are times changing are they not
funding terrorism anymore and Priyanka
tja says are we heading towards some
serious escalation in West Asia
considering the recent El attack on the
Golden Heights is it worrisome for India
please share your thoughts on this okay
okay
so there's a lot that's happened of late
in West Asia so once again let's take a
look at the the the map of the region
West Asia is the this region you know uh
so Iraq Iran is kind of you know between
the subcontinent and West Asia I would
not call it a middle eastern or West
Asian Nation technically you could even
say that you could even argue that it's
part of the Indian subcontinent
extension of the Indian subcontinent but
for the purpose of this uh of answering
this question let's say Iran is kind of
part of the West Asian landscape or
middle Eastern landscape so what's
happened is that the Hamas Chief is was
in tan he was he attended the
inauguration of the new Iranian
president because the previous president
was unfortunately uh killed in an
aircraft accident a helicopter crash now
i' I've said this so many times don't
use helicopters they're not as stable as
fixed Wing aircraft but people don't
listen anyhow so that's what happened so
so a few hours after this guy Han
attends the inauguration of the new
president apparently he killed and the
Iranians say that it is the Zionist
regime like they say which means Israel
that is behind the assassination
Apparently one hears that there was a
either a drone strike or a cruise
missile strike on the room in which Mr
hany was staying and he was taken out he
he got
killed uh so if that is true it means
that Iran has been humiliated by the
Israelis because come on on inan a few
hours after meeting the president that
is humiliating and it it tells you that
Iran's security appar is terrible and it
also tells the world that Israel can
strike anybody anywhere they want
anytime no matter who's being who is
protecting that person uh so that is a
situation
now do we have any evidence okay so
that's done with the map now the
question is
this what's the evidence that anyone has
in the public domain
that the Israelis have killed Mr Han do
we have any evidence the the Iranians
have claimed that this has happened that
the Israel has killed him but what's the
evidence we haven't even seen Mr honey
is sadly unfortunately dead body okay
yeah okay see look he's a terrorist
Hamas is a terrorist organization Etc
but the point is we haven't seen the
dead body we haven't seen the location
where this attack happened we haven't
seen any evidence of any explosion
somewhere of a drone strike or a cruise
missile strike or whatever it was so we
don't have any actual evidence that
backs up what the Iranians have claimed
what so let's play Devils Advocate over
here I'm not saying this is what
happened I'm saying what if this is the
case what if the Iranians for whatever
reason decided to ratchet up tensions
with with Israel by taking out Mr honey
and then blaming it on the
Israelis look it's not beyond the realm
of possibility in a chanakan world in a
cian world anything's possible so once
again we don't have any evidence the
that the Iranians have done this we
don't even have any evidence that Mr
honey is dead maybe he's alive
somewhere um you know just like Elvis is
still alive apparently somewhere maybe
even Michael Jackson is alive so M maybe
Mr hone is also alive and they've
only you know faked his assassination
like uh what is that movie James B movie
You Only Live Twice or something yes
Sean conry so maybe you know so in the
absence of any
evidence any you know all the all the
possible scenarios all the potential
scenarios are in are in play so I don't
know what's really happened I have seen
no evidence that he is dead or alive or
that he's alive we don't know we have no
evidence that he has that he has
appeared in public after the date and we
have no evidence that he's actually dead
so we don't know what's happened the
Israelis they deny any any
involvement in in whatever may have
happened so it it is possible that the
irgc may have been behind this if it's
if he's actually dead but we have no
evidence of that either so all of that
is in play right now it's a
superposition of States it's like a
quantum mechanical system in which you
know the cat is dead and alive and
Undead and everything at the same time
that sort of situation so that is the
deal with Mr Hy now Sam says the Arabs
have kept quiet on this matter
are times changing are they not funding
terrorism anymore the Arabs want peace
the AR Arabs want development if you
look at the UAE the UAE is a fast
developing Nation they want foreign
investment they want to develop their
country they want a peaceful stable
country they want foreigners to come and
settle down in their country there are
so many expats who live in the UAE
Indian expats Western experts Etc they
don't want any War they want stability
they want growth they want development
that's the UAE what about Saudi Arabia
the big the big Power in West Asia the
Saudis also want peace prosperity
stability um their their de facto ruler
Mr Muhammad bin Salman has so many plans
for transforming his Nation um and
taking the economy Beyond simply being
dependent on oil so many plans they have
they even wanted the the India the IMC
to happen the India middle east Europe
trade Corridor which bypasses turkey
the Saudi Saudi Arabia is is is the
major portion of the IM you know so the
Arabic Nations don't want any of this
nonsense they don't want any War they
don't want any any terrorism the Saudis
have cracked down hard on
terrorism the UAE doesn't want terrorism
none of these nations in the Middle East
want terrorism all of them have
excellent relations with India that's
also another coincidental factor or
maybe not a coincidence so in the past
we know there was all kinds of stuff you
know know Terror funding coming in from
this region in the past times have
genuinely changed so the Arabs don't
want anything to do with these M this
matter okay the Arabs don't have the
best of of relations with the with the
Iranians that's an old historical Grudge
going back roughly 13400 years which
will not go into but uh so the Arabs
don't want any of this they they just
want peace and they they are deeply
unhappy with the situation that has
unfolded since October last year when
this entire thing happened and Hamas
attacked Israel in a horrific terrorist
attack Etc and everything has gone
downhill from there the Arabs don't want
this it's it's bad for the region it's
bad for their
economies um and Priyanka asks about are
we heading towards
escalation uh I'm not aware of any
attack on the Golan Heights but this is
what's happened the Han thing maybe I
missed if there's been an attack on the
Golan Hees uh but yeah there's going to
be some some kind of escalation the
Iranians have made this public claim
that the Israelis assassinated Han on
their territory in their Capital so
after making such a claim they are
essentially they have to retaliate in
some manner now once again if you look
at the map the distance between Iran and
Israel is is roughly a, kilometers the
Iranians don't have great Air Force they
cannot launch air strikes on Israel this
they have have good ballistic missiles
and cruise missiles but the Israelis
have a good defense system called the
iron doome that can take out many of
these incoming ballistic or cruise
missiles the Iranians have excellent
drones but even that can be kind of uh
dealt with with the kind of defensive
measures the Israelis and other nations
have so in the past we know what
happened right there was an
assassination done by Israel apparently
on um Iranian Generals in in in Syria
and Iran retaliated with a massive drone
strike and missile strike and most of
these drones and missiles were
neutralized and those that indeed did
hit targets within Israel did not cause
any major D damage they did not take out
any high value targets so that kind of
was a failed uh attack you know kind of
a fa failure so if the Iranians do that
again and it fails again again then it
kind of humiliates them further you know
and they can't carry out air attacks
because they don't have a powerful Air
Force so what can Iran do Iran will have
to do something after making such a
claim otherwise they look well truthless
important uh Etc powerless that's not a
good look for any Nation so most likely
there could be some kind of proxy
attacks either via Hamas or hasbullah or
the yemenis proxies that the Iranians
have have the
houis ETC or or cyber attacks or or some
kind of other Terror attacks Etc could
happen Okay that's that's what I could
uh you know potentially see happening
obviously we don't want any escalation
of the situation but that's where we are
so there's going to be some escalation
and if that happens Israel Israelis will
obviously retaliate and that could raise
the
temperature in the region that's where
we are what's the sit what what's the
deal with India how should India look at
this is is worrisome for India well if
there is escalation of tensions and and
all that then what could happen is that
the if the houis get involved for
example from Yemen and there are attacks
on on on ships Etc then and there are
drone strikes and all that and maybe Air
Force activity from Israel then you
could see the Strait of hormos getting
closed this this region this Gap is
called the state of hormos which
connects the Persian Gulf with the uh
with the Indian Ocean
the Sea of sashtra and that could be a
disaster for for the global economy and
the Indian economy because uh a lot of
the world's energy flows out of the
porian gulf oil yeah so that would be
terrible so that's one that that that
could be bad news for the world economy
especi and that includes the Indian
economy now how should India look at
this this entire matter are are we
Indians Duty bound to take sides lots of
Indians feel that we have to take sides
in this matter that we should either
choose this side or that side and most
Indians obviously are are favorably
inclined towards Israel for a variety of
reasons my point is this is not our
fight we did not start this fight we we
are not part of this fight and we have
reasonably good relations with Israel as
well as Iran Iran is in no way a hostile
Nation to India Iran doesn't Target
India in any way the way Pakistan has
historically done of course if you go
back to 1965 then the Sha of Iran who
was a US puppet uh sided with Pakistan
and you can go back a couple of few
centuries and you have the attack of
Nadar sha on India but NAD sha was not a
person he was a
turk it was NAD sha was to Iran what
orze was to India okay he was a Turk NAD
sha and he attacked India and he
committed Slaughter genocide in
Delhi uh but he was not persan like I
said so historically look we don't have
any major tensions with Iran we are not
adversary Nations we are not
enemies Iran doesn't do anything that
harms India uh in any significant way U
and that's a situation and obviously
when it comes to Israel we have very
good relations with with
Israel uh Israel as we know aided India
during the Cargill War when the
Americans shut off the GPS uh access to
to India uh obviously the Israelis could
not provide GPS access to India but they
sold some arms ammunition artillery
supplies Etc to India that sort of thing
uh but Israel also has shown a
preference in the past of of preferring
China or India when it comes to economic
activities Etc so look every nation has
its own interests there there are no
warm uh cultural ties between India and
Israel or India and Iran any anymore so
from our perspective I would say that we
should not take
sides we don't need to get emotionally
invested in in in a fight
between two Nations that that that
doesn't involve us okay we don't have a
horse in that race like I say we don't
have a dog in that fight it's nothing to
do with us we should simply urge both
Nations to deescalate and to negotiate
their way out of the situation that's
what we should say but we have no need
to take sides Indians for some reason
feel this need to take sides whenever
there's a fight somewhere if there's a
war happening in Ukraine Oh we must
either support Ukraine or Russia how
about being neutral what does it have to
do with us so be practical be be
pragmatic look geopolitics is an immoral
sport there's no morality in geopolitics
there's no right or wrong there's only
interests and what you should support is
India's
interests that's it
you don't need to take this nation's
side or that nation's side you have to
be on the side of India the only nation
you need to support is India and when
others fight you the best we can do is
to urge them to deescalate and stop
fighting and negotiate diplomacy is the
way forward and that's what our refrain
has been since 2022 when the Ukraine
situation started
unfolding negotiate diplomacy please
stop fighting this is not a time for war
so that is the right
approach okay next
question aha here we go so Zuma arnab
kt55 and rajat chobra have asked
questions and there have been many more
questions about Bangladesh but I could
not fill up the whole screen with that
so I've taken three questions as
representative of all those questions so
uh the question is about what's
happening in Bangladesh do what do you
think about the students protesting in
Bangladesh make a video on Bangladesh
students protest and reveal the real
agenda and truth behind it is the
Bangladeshi students protest Justified
is the shik hen government
dictatorial so uh there's been a lot of
chatter on social media lots of people
are and even Indians who are saying
there are lots of Indians who have been
saying that the shikina is has turned
into a dictator and she's crushing the
poor innocent students
aspirations and there's been some some
Kota thing look you know student
protests are a tried and tested method
method for for affecting regime change
in various
Nations okay students can be very easily
made to do things which they have no
comprehension of take some issue any
random issue in the country have the
professors inflame the sentiments of the
students because professors are persons
in authority and we in the subcontinent
are slavish towards Authority right we
we
wholeheartedly do whatever those in
Authority tell us we believe them we
worship them we regard them with
reverance Etc especially we in the
subcontinent no matter what our religion
is we have this ingrain in us that those
who teach us are our gurus well in
today's education system including in
Pakistan Bangladesh Etc your teachers
aren't your gurus they are your service
providers that's not what a guru does
what these teachers do anyhow so it's so
easy it's incredibly easy to manipulate
the sentiments of students to inflame
their their uh emotions and to get them
to you know do Mass protests Etc if you
control the Academia and most academic
uh systems in the subcontinent are are
well you could say deeply influenced by
uh outside external actors especially
Western act actors with with Deep
Pockets also China confusious institutes
Etc
so
uh so with that understood we have to
understand the uh role that Bangladesh
plays in the subcontinent obviously I'm
sure you all know where Bangladesh is
it's right next to India it is East
Bengal historically part of India for
thousands of years but now it's a
separate nation since
so shik Hina the prime minister of
Bangladesh is pro is a pro-india leader
and India and Bangladesh have been
working together on a number of issues
and it's been a very very uh positive
uh relationship we have had with
Bangladesh ever since she has become the
leader the the the the prime minister of
Bangladesh
so as of
today Bangladesh is one of the few
nations in the subcontinent that is
genuinely Pro India look at Nepal it is
deeply influenced by the Chinese and the
Americans and it is overall the the
political climate is anti-india Nepal
Bhutan finds itself caught between a
rock and a hard place
there is that Myanmar is in Civil War
Sri Lanka well it's it's been pro-china
for for well especially when the Raja
pakas were in power we know what's
happening in the Maldives Pro China
Pakistan the less we speak about it the
better Afghanistan well okay not overall
a bad relationship and Iran overall
reasonably good relationship but
Bangladesh is the only nation that is
genuinely pro-india it's because shik
Hina is pro India
and so and the Americans want regime
change in Bangladesh and shikina has has
taken the unprecedented step of making
the allegation multiple times that the
Americans have been trying to interfere
in Bangladeshi politics there was a
general election earlier this year that
that shika won she became she won for
the third consecutive time and the
Americans wanted to oust her the
Americans wanted the opposition to come
to power and they actually told her okay
that they would be okay with to support
her if she allowed the Americans to
carve out a Christian Nation out of some
parts of Bangladesh and that Christian
Nation will be kooki land it will also
include parts of India and parts of
Burma and apart from that the Americans
also want an island from the Bangladeshi
okay there's this island South of
Bangladesh it's a Bangladeshi Island the
Americans want to create a military base
there this little island called St
Martin's Island I don't know why it's
called St Martin's Island for for
whatever reason but that's what they
call it so the Americans want to build a
military base over here Air Force Base
and Naval base from which they can
project power to threaten various
nations in the region kind of like Diego
Garcia the illegally occupied uh Moran
archipelago where the Americans have a
massive uh Naval and Air Force Bas this
one here they acquired this in 1973
after their disastrous performance in
1971 the war in which India liberated
Bangladesh the Americans want to
consolidate their position in the Bay of
Bengal region the Kalinga SE region so
all of that is happening and the leader
of Bangladesh Miss shikina has not uh
allowed the Americans to do any of this
and which that's why they are now
ramping up the pressure on her through
these uh
artificially uh astroturfed student
protests very similar to things that
have happened in India in the past in
the past few years suddenly protest
emerging out of nowhere whether it is
Farmers or whatever it is right and
similar things have happened in Thailand
in the past 2020 21 there were sudden
student protests in Bangkok and various
parts of Thailand anti-monarchy protests
because apparently the Thai government
wasn't willing to do certain things okay
and such things have happened in various
other parts of the world so this is a
regime change operation okay whatever
the the justification for it it's simply
an
excuse you can make anything into a into
the pretext for a protest okay for
demonstrations take any issue and you
can have students protest on that
doesn't matter what the issue is doesn't
matter at all uh so shik is not
dictatorial she's won three elections
you know the Americans if their pet
candidate doesn't win they say it's it's
dictatorship if their pet candidate wins
they say it's
democracy they they who are they to
adjudicate the the result of Elections
and and to and to give U you know a
certificate of whether you Democratic or
di who are they the the entire so-called
rules-based World Order is premised the
premise of this is sovereignty and non-
interference no nation is permitted to
permitted to interfere in the internal
matters of other nations but the
Americans routinely trample over this
principle routinely but they call this
the world rules based World Order which
is the whims of the us-based world order
so what's happening in Bangladesh is a
US attempt to change the regime in
banglades Bangladesh to to OU shik hassa
from power and there what will this
enable the Americans to do it'll enable
them to first of all acquire a
Bangladesh Island to create a military
base from on secondly it'll enable them
to carve out a new artificial Christian
Nation called kooki land out of
Bangladesh out of Burma and out of
Manipur in
mizoram and that artificial Nation will
cut off India's access to Southeast Asia
so that is what's happening it's a
geopolitical thing what's happening in
the region it's all interconnected the
Burma situation the Manipur situation
the Bangladesh situation the student
student protest in Bangladesh it's all
inter connected the drug situation in
India's Far East the poppy plantations
that the uh illegal infiltrators have
been setting up for the past few years
all that it's all
interconnected so that's a
deal
next geopolitical du says what's the
current situation in Burma how do you
foresee the future of Burma
hypothetically asking if Burma collapses
and wants to merge with parat what will
happen Okay since we are speaking about
Bangladesh we can speak about Burma
Myanmar our neighboring Nation so in
case you don't know you're not aware
it's a pretty large Nation east of India
India's Faris nagaland Manipur mizoram
it all and arunachal Pradesh it all
borders Burma and parts of Bangladesh
also border Burma and Burma neighbors uh
China also Laos Thailand Laos in
Thailand so pretty large nation and
right now there is chaos in Burma so so
there's a there's a total breakdown of
Law and Order there is a civil war
situation happening over there lots of
different ethnic groups are fighting the
burmes government the military hun like
they
say and the Burmese government the
military government it controls now less
than I would say less than half of the
nation it looks like uh so they're under
a lot of pressure and there is a lot of
foreign involvement in the situation
there's this tremendous Supply of arms
and ammunition and bullets and artillery
shells and whatnot that these for the
these ethnic groups and their local
militias have access to from where one
wonders obviously China is a factor
China is China has a significantly long
border with Burma China is a factor and
Thailand also has a very large border
with
Burma and yeah so take your guest take
your choice so there is a civil war
situation in Burma what's the future of
Burma it looks BMA will break up the
Americans will be able to affect that
and by doing that they can you know
create chaos in India as well as China
the Chinese are not a democratic Nation
they are dictatorship so they have much
better control of what's happening in
the region but in India the situation
isn't that good we have allowed foreign
religions and all that to to encroach
Upon Our territory and right now if you
look at the far East of India it's been
significantly
well christianized okay and there's an
very strong involvement of foreign
missionaries Baptist missionaries in the
ongoing Civil War in Myanmar in
Burma uh so it looks like Burma may
break up it may fragment and parts of it
will be used by the Americans to create
cookie land but the real cookie land
they want to carve out out of parts of
Bangladesh and the Indian uh territories
states of Manipur and missor
and even if it is not officially made
into an official Nation it could become
a def facto Nation if the Americans
succeed in their
Ploy okay so it will be technically and
officially part of India but uh you will
have foreign militants collecting taxes
and running the administration which is
already happening in parts of Manipur
okay Southern Manipur Etc uh so yeah
it's it's a dire situation right now and
India has its hands full and the future
of the region is up for grabs right now
so if Burma collapses will it want to
join with bat who will want to merge
with bhat who which government which
people which authority if Burma
collapses as may happen it may fragment
and break up and you'll have lots of
little ethnic groups who will claim
Sovereign claim Independence Etc but
yeah it will not happen and uh so the
situation is not like it will it will
want to with bat the situation is which
could happen is that it will want to
claim territory from bat this new nation
of Cil land okay so that is what India
is up against right now and the
situation this entire matter there's no
immediate solution to that the roots of
the problem are ancient going back to
the British times the British see
wherever there is chaos in the world if
you go back in history and look at the
roots of the conflict you will find the
British involved there the British
started this then Mr Neu made things
terribly worse by allowing foreigners to
change the demographics and culture and
religion in the Far East of India and
now the past few years there's been this
tremendous influx of foreigners into
India and that's caused the situation
these foreigners are not even burmes by
the way okay they don't speak the burmes
language they don't respect burmes
culture they're fighting the burmes
government so the future of Burma to
answer your question looks dire right
now the nation may break up may fragment
a new nations may emerge out of that and
that's the overall objective that the
Americans
have Rema Das says in one of the recent
ask of episodes you explained how Europe
is orchestrating a mass christianization
campaign in Northeast India Far East
India and neighboring countries then why
are they allowing the demography of
European nations to change with such
large scale immigration it seems
ironically counterproductive and doesn't
make sense to me what's the purpose
behind this that's a good question
excellent question remad so
so it's not Europe that's
behind the mass christianization that's
happened in India's Far East the mass
christianization the roots of that go
back to the 19th century when the
British were doing this and uh after
India's independence Mr Neu for forbade
any Hindu religious uh people from going
into the region and he brought in lots
of American Baptist missionaries to
completely change the demographics
religious demographics of places like
nagaland Etc on an industrial scale and
it succeeded brilliantly so it happened
in the 19th and 20th Centuries by the
late 20th century most of nagaland was
christianized mizoram is already anyway
christianized because they all well mizo
zi same thing so all that um so it's not
the Europeans who did that
the Baptist missionaries were American
missionaries okay and Europe is not a
geopolitical actor it's an economic
actor sure it's not a geopolitical actor
Europe is not a sovereign region none of
the European nations are sovereign
Nations the genuine the only Sovereign
power in Western Europe is the United
States the US controls Europe whether it
is through the European Union or through
NATO so if you are a member of the EU
you don't have full sovereignty you have
pooled sovereignty you have to give up
some sovereignty to the
EU and it's Brussels that will decide
the fate of your nation and what happens
in your nation and the policies economic
policies and other policies and that's
why immigration is happening in Europe
okay so first of all Europe isn't doing
this Europe did not do this in the 20th
century the UK did that in the 19th
century and in the early 20th century as
long as they were there in power and
after that it's been the US that did
this the mass Christian ization in the
Far East of India Europe was not part of
that let me repeat that now so now that
we understand that the Americans were
behind this now let's understand what's
happening in Europe there is mass
immigration in Europe a couple of
nations are holding out like Hungary
Poland Etc but the other nations have
opened their borders and embraced these
immigrants who are generally from the
Middle East from from West Asia or from
Africa very few women and children
mostly military age men young
males
and that is what's happening in Europe
so uh the Europeans have no seem to have
no agency in this all the nations in
Europe they simply have to obey whatever
Brussels tells them Brussels is the is
where the European Union's it's the
European Union's administrative Center
the power center Etc and who controls
the it's the US that controls the EU so
the Americans are
essentially uh behind one could say the
uh attempt
toine re-engineer the demographics of
Europe and it's obviously working and uh
there is some push back from various
parts of Europe I mean right now there's
a riot situation going on in the UK the
native indigenous people of the UK are
trying to protest the large scale
immigration that's happening in the
UK
well it won't succeed I guess and we
know the situation in France there are
riots from time to time Paris was under
siege multiple times last
year um and similar situations in
various parts of Europe so the natives
are power even in Ireland now it started
okay Mass immigration Spain it's
happening it's happening everywhere
Italy bad situation already so the
natives of Europe are
helpless somebody some power the only
Power that's really in charge of Europe
is the us since 1945 so they are now
essentially reengineering the
demographics of
Europe the U ethnic demographics as well
as religious demographics of Europe and
there is mass immigration happening in
the US also yeah people from various
third world Nations entering illegally
the Democrats are engineering that so
all that is happening is it
counterproductive no it's all about
control it's all about controlling these
nations the nativist sentiment should be
smashed for example Germany okay the
Americans when they think of
Germany today's Germany they still see
this picture of those marching boots in
those Hugo Boss uniforms na uniforms
they still see that and the Nazis had
this idea of racial Purity they had
stolen the term Arian from
us and it was all about white supremacy
European Supremacy the master race the
Uber mench all that so what if you
simply dilute the the ethnic
demographics of Germany and have the
German population mixed with people from
West Asia and and and Africa then there
is no white race left anymore and the
entire fear disappears because there's
no master allegedly Master race that
exists anymore know that's how you
neutralize Nations that's how we
neutralize Nations how were the Native
Americans neutralized if you go to the
US today and you stumble upon somebody
who has Native American ethnicity you'll
find that none of them are pure Native
American they're all mixed with the
European
settlers there are very few pureblood
Native Americans left in the US or in
Canada that's how you destroy a people
that's how you destroy an ethnicity by
having them well mix with settlers and
colonizers so there is an attempt that's
happening right now to to change the
religious and ethnic demographics of
Europe so that Europe is no longer is
never a threat again and then it can be
controlled through various
means so it's not happening so all these
mass christianization that happened in
India's Far East and whatever is
happening in various other parts of
India right now for example Punjab for
for example Nepal Nepal obviously is not
part of India but part of the
subcontinent all of that is being
engineered well recently you know it was
in the news that the
Americans um via certain proxies had
allocated significant amounts of funds
for uh the propagation of Christianity
in Nepal and we know what's happening in
Punjab okay industrial scale conversion
of mostly six to Christianity most of
this is coming out of the US okay so
it's not Europe that's behind this it's
the United
States and what do you achieve by by by
christianizing a region you achieve the
ask the Japanese ask the Chinese the
Chinese and the Japanese wrote about
this they said that they wrote about
this in the 18th and 19th centuries
let's talk about the Chinese 19th
century the the Opium Wars the Chinese
wrote that when people convert to a
western religion they developed extr
territorial
loyalties yeah so that's the objective
and I'll stop at
that Ramesh Kar says recently our frate
ship ins brahmaputra fell into the water
such events are happening repeatedly
over the past few years not only with
ships but with submarines also is this
because except a few most of them are
more than 20 years old shouldn't we have
a strong and upto-date Naval Force for
good hold of the Sea of sashtra the
so-called Arabian Sea so here yes I will
not put the images on the screen because
they're distressing but the ins
brahmaputra recently
capsized in Mumbai there this okay let's
see the map I not show the image of of
the ship but we can see the images the
map of the region so we have Mumbai the
major city in Western India India's
Financial Capital Mumbai is here now if
you look at the port in
Mumbai okay this is all open source
information I'm not showing anything
that's classified okay it's available on
Google Maps for God's sake
so uh where is this port is the question
right okay so the Gateway of India and
if we would you please remove that here
there we go so here over here behind the
Gateway of India north of it north east
of the Gateway of India we have this
Mumbai port and if you take a look at
the kind of ships you have there it
becomes very obvious that there are very
interesting ships
here these are submarines as you can see
now submarines aren't civilian ships
these are military ships naval ships and
much more you can see I mean you can
take your pick and look at what's how
many submarines you can see over
here so that's the situation in Mumbai
you have this Naval Port that is right
next to ballad Pier Etc where you have
Cruise Ships coming in so you will have
tourists standing right next to
submarines taking picture of submarines
and Indian Naval assets this is not a
good situation I simply don't understand
how we can allow this to happen you know
people Chinese tourists can take a a
ferry from the Gateway of India and go
this way okay so and and go to this
island over here gharapuri island or
so-called Elephant Island and along the
way they can take pictures of Indian
naval ships Indian submarines and if
they have good cameras and also
also the uh Baba Atomic Research Center
nuclear reactors or
here okay there are I don't know where
exactly it is but you have nuclear
reactors which are visible from the Fay
so we have our critical infrastructure
over here are extremely
important assets that are in full view
of of uh foreign Nationals and you have
this port which is a dual use port you
have Cruise Ships coming in from various
parts of the world and they are an you
know putting down anchor right next to
India's precious military
assets isn't this a
security I been a very bad security
situation isn't
this something has to be done about this
you can't
have our military assets right next to I
mean they should not be visible to to
civilians but that's what we have and
there's been there have been other
accidents over here in Mumbai I think it
was in 2013 that ins synu rakak a
submarine caught fire and exploded and
and sank and I don't know how many
sailors died in that accident in that
incident not accident incident and more
than 10 Sailors died if I'm not mistaken
in synura we lost that sumary one of the
few submarines we have we had U and
there have been other accidents as well
so there is something fishy going on in
this in this port in Mumbai and uh I
don't know why it is the case why isn't
this being investigated properly and why
aren't these security lapses let's say
being nipped in the bud identify the
source the root of these lapses whatever
is going wrong and rectify take the
right action I don't know what the hell
is going
on so that's where we are when it comes
to Mumbai yeah you're right such are
happening often if you have even three
accidents in 10 years that's
bad uh so there are obvious security
risks over here obvious security risk
you will find tourists posting pictures
on Instagram or whatnot with submarines
behind them Indian
submarines how can you have that
happen uh and of course you're right
that many of our Naval assets are old
some of them are more than 20 years old
some of them are even older
um so I agree that uh there are all
these problems not just in Mumbai I'm
sure there are other places where they
need to look into the the matter as well
such similar things um we need to have a
very powerful navy look we we are see
let me show you the map once again
because the map tells you everything you
need to know so let's zoom out of Mumbai
look India's access to Eurasia is cut
off by Pakistan and China Pakistan
occupies parts of Kashmir because of and
of that we no longer have access to
Afghanistan we no longer have access to
Tajikistan or Tibet Tibet we have access
to but it is controlled by China China
is occupied Tibet so our historic access
to sou to to Eurasia Central Asia and
Eurasia has been cut off for the past 70
75 80
years and we have absolutely no
infrastructure in the Far East of India
that can connect us with let's say
Thailand we have no roads that go to
Cambodia Vietnam no Railways nothing we
have done nothing whatsoever we've been
sleeping the past 75 years so because of
that we are essentially a landlock
nation almost and the only access to the
rest of the world we have is by sea so
it is extremely and we have this God
gifted geographical position that
dominates the entire Indian Ocean region
so how can we take advantage of it by
develop by building a powerful navy that
can project power well beyond our Shores
but we we have not done that we have a
good Navy we have a strong Navy probably
the strongest Navy in the region but it
is I would say we need to do much much
more we need to dominate the region we
need to be visible wherever anyone goes
in the Indian Ocean region even south of
the Equator why not we have some some
Assets in the
region but we do we certainly can do
more we need to become a major dominant
dominating Maritime power
and uh I don't see that ambition
unfortunately I don't see that ambition
we have limited resources and what are
we doing with those resources we
investing we are investing in
concentrated lethality while we should
be investing in distributed lethality
which is way scarier and way more
effective but yeah we have Geniuses and
we have very intelligent people and
experts eminent experts who say that we
should have more concentrated lethality
Naval in in in the naval sense if you
know what I mean then you know what I
mean
okay Prine garti says the US has
declared edmundo Gonzalez the winner of
the Venezuelan election Secretary of
State Shri Anthony J blinken in a newly
released statement challenged the
official results of Venezuela's
presidential election asserting that
opposition candidate edmundo Gonzalez
ruia is the legitimate winner of the
July 28 what not Mr Nicolas
Maduro one should wonder why the US
believes that it knows the results of
the elections of foreign Nations more
than the Nations themselves who are the
Americans who declare results in Nations
that are not the US it's a good question
and the US does this on a routine basis
they are the world's super cop they are
the world's only policeman they are the
global super cop and they are the sole
and final Arbiter globally of what is
democratic and what is not Democratic
and now they are they have begun to
announce the result of elections in
nations in other
nations um so yeah
look I would say that why you I'll say
why are you surprised by this they can
so they do
it they have earned the right to be this
hypocritical by being by becoming so
powerful they're the only superpower in
the world
and so that's what they do so in the
future they may declare results in
Thailand or declare results in in in I
don't know India someday they may do it
to India as well if we are not
careful
so once again let me talk about the
rules-based world order the Americans
keep on harping about international law
that's so and so thing goes against
international law so and so thing goes
against international law this is not
right that is not right we need to
respect international law we need to
respect the international rules-based
World Order now what is this rules-based
world order predicated upon what
principles is it predicated upon what is
international law so-called
international law predicated upon what
are the pillars of international law and
the rules-based world order the first
pillar is sovereignty and
non-interference that every nation every
Sovereign Nation that is recognized by
the UN and other
countries has the right to sovereignty
which means exclusive control over its
territory and its population and then
there's no interference which means that
every nation no Nation can interfere is
allowed to interfere or has the right to
interfere in the internal matters of
other
nations these are the two fundamental
pillars apart from others of the
rules-based World Order of the
international of international law and
the Americans have a selective approach
to that when it suits them they'll
trample upon this and when it sus them
they'll lecture Nations about
this so that's obviously double
standards it's a hypocrisy and my point
is that you have to earn the right to be
hypocritical by becoming powerful the
more powerful you are the more
hypocritical you can
be um so the rest of the world simply
those who are not powerful enough simply
have to swallow
it and and that's just the way the world
is the strong Rule and the
weak Bend to their
will um so that's the situation and
maybe look today in the world of the
internet social media Etc we can also
declare the results of elections right
and if they can declare the results of
elections in other countries maybe other
countries can also adjudicate what
happens in the US there's going to be an
election
soon yeah maybe Venezuela should
announce the
winner and you know give it back to the
US okay
SRX dj8 GB okay yeah asks is a union of
turkic people from the alai mountain
region to Turkey via East Turkmenistan
ever possible okay good question let's
take a look at the map where is this
alai mountain region is the question so
it's I'll I'll show you how to locate
that very easily it's it's where
kazakistan Mongolia Russia and China
meet that region is the Alti mountain
region the Alti mountain range is in the
region where you kind of have a junction
of four nations there are two Tri
Junctions here so this region is the is
where you have the alai mountains
historically it was part of the mongolic
territories okay the Mongol people so
that's the Ala mountain region and
obviously the turkey culture has also
emerged from this region and kazakistan
is a turkic nation all the other Stans
apart from Tajikistan are turkic
nations and the uh
Chinese region of shinjang especially
the urumi ETC region is East turkistan
which is also
Turk where you have the ugur people who
who who inhabit the region okay so this
entire region is inhabited by turkic
ethnicity people and Turk speaking
people they speak various turkic
languages and obviously you also have
turky people in Russia okay the tat
Tatar people Etc and various other
peoples
there's a significant Turkey population
in a very large part of Eurasia and it
goes all the way to Turkey aeran is a
turkic nation Georgia and Armenia are
not turkic Nations and neither is the
Caucasus region which is more of an
iranic region ethnically and
linguistically but you have turkey over
here in the Mediterranean region in
Anatolia so that is the geography of the
question now the question is is a union
of the turkey people
which which spans this entire
geographical extent is it
possible well nothing is impossible and
the Turks especially Mr erdogan would
like to make this happen and to make
that happen he will have to erase a
couple of nations from the map one is
Armenia the other is Georgia Georgia
obviously they will not go into but they
will they would want to erase the small
ancient nation of Armenia from from the
map of the world so that turkey can
connect with aeran fully and across the
sea across the Caspian Sea they can
connect with turkistan and the other
turky Nations and they can create this
span Turan Corridor Turan is the tur
Homeland so to say so they want to make
this happen they would like to see this
happen but uh it goes against the
interests of Nations like Russia and
even the Americans wouldn't want this to
happen so it is possible but it is
difficult for the turky peoples to
achieve this because of the interests of
more powerful world
powers Saint crocodile says what are
your views on the woke Madness that
happened in the Olympics opening
ceremony how will this woke opening
ceremony affect the political scenario
of France and Europe as a whole look
what what we witnessed during the
opening ceremony of the Olympics is not
something that will affect the political
scenario of France and Europe it is not
something that will affect the scenario
it is a symptom of the political climate
in the region okay it's a symptom it's a
manifestation of the politics of the
political climate the dominant political
narrative in climate in the west not
just in France and Europe but overall in
the west all of this has
emanated well if you trace it back it it
all emenates out of France going back a
couple of centuries but
uh one could
argue that wokeism started in
France la rolu Fran the French
Revolution was was the first voke
Revolution one could say one can even go
back further back in time but we can
start from France you
know lowering of Standards targeting the
nobility beheading maranet and her
husband Louis the 16th and in the
Olympics opening ceremony they had
maret's decapitated head sing some song
I didn't see the whole thing but was
Gastly to see that um celebrating the
murder of their Queen a couple of
centuries ago roughly
still doing that and all all all the
other things that they displayed in the
opening ceremony Gastly absolutely
Gastly and they made fun of Leonard the
winch's last supper right which involves
Jesus Christ now I'm not Christian I
have no great love for any any any
religion apart from my own but I was
kind of offended by seeing that what are
you people doing to your own culture I
mean it is your own culture now the
Europeans once had a pre-christian
culture but that's been smashed out of
existence more than more than a thousand
years ago
and for a thousand years most Europeans
have been believing in this one this
specific religion Christianity and now
and even today lots of Europeans
practice Christianity and look at what
the
powers the ones who are in power look at
what they're doing they're mocking their
religion they're mocking their culture
and they are mocking their powerlessness
to do anything about this sad to see
that but that's what Europe is going
through right
now so so
um and and there was like some of that
was quite Gastly there was this uh this
particular segment in which there was
this blue guy guy dressed in blue in a
Blue Dress apparently dionis the the
Greek one of the Greek gods God of
alcoholism I guess some people claim
that it's a Greek representation of
Shiva but I'm not quite sure about that
but it was not about honoring the
pre-christian gods of Europe or Greek
gods it was about disparaging the
culture that most Europeans follow
today uh so yeah it was it's what it
is um so wokeness is is is in control
it's in power
now and the people of Europe are
essentially helpless to do anything
about it that's what it tells you so
there's no democracy in Europe if the
there was genuine democracy then these
parties and these politicians that that
espouse these views they would not be in
power but they are so there's no
democracy in Europe today none
whatsoever Raj chobra says are IM khif
allegations valid let's figure out who
IM khif is shall
we so let's go to our friend Google and
so this is to do with the Olympics and
boxing and women's boxing to be more
specific
imif so this is a boxer who compet reped
in women's boxing
okay and it's a male person with XY
chromosomes not XX chromosomes the way
women have and this individual competed
in women's boxing and he beat up an
Italian boxer the poor girl she broke
down in tears she had to withdraw from
the fight and now this guy is going to
win a medal
apparently okay and this person is
Algerian I believe
and in
Algeria It generally women wear hijabs
right it's an Islamic Nation this is the
the the Italian girl was beaten up by
the
guy uh now
uh so um childhood
photos so as a child this this person
looked like a girl but as he grew up it
was very clear it was a man
and there was some some something
abnormal about this person's genitals
which made him and his parents initially
believe that it was a girl but uh once
puberty sets in it becomes very obvious
what your actual gender
is and yeah so
uh so look if you look at the person's
physique and look at the overall thing
it's very clear it's it's it's a male
so the point is he it's it's it's a
person with XY chromosomes not a person
with XX chromosomes and from my
perspective from a scientific
perspective biological perspective males
are XY and women are females are XX this
person is XY One X chromosome one Y
chromosome that makes that person a male
and is clearly stronger than girls so I
guess he's going to win a gold or at
least he's already assured of a medal so
well that's how it is and do you
remember DTI Chand there was this Indian
uh there is this uh Indian athlete
called DTI
Chand this is a girl it's a lady and she
was it was alleged that she has
excessive testosterone something
testosterone or something like that a
few years ago and she was barred by the
Olympic Association or whatever it is
from competing for a few
years and so so that's how an Indian
athlete was treated but when it comes to
this this Algerian guy is allowed to
compete uh as a woman in a woman's Sport
and beat up beat up women I think it's
it's it's a travesty of Justice it's
it's
tragic and uh why don't have multiple
self- declared females competing in
women's disciplines and they can then
compete for the the gold and various
medals I'd say that you know what Mike
Tyson should announce that I now
identify as a woman and he should enter
women's boxing and then let's see what
happens if if that's all it takes to
become a woman or whatever gender you
want that I now identify so and so then
why should then I said Mike Tyson should
enter women's boxing and let him show
his left hook or her left hook Mika
Tyson it's just ridiculous the
situation okay Imran naimi says does
poetry in European languages lack the
poetic qualities of languages like Hindi
Arabic and Dari do these languages have
different poetic forms there is Magic in
Hindi and Dari poetry and I get
overwhelmed when I read them they're
philosophical and
suggestive um is is other poetry more
profound than let's say European poetry
well I am reasonably familiar with
European poetry the classics William
birdsworth and whatnot I've even read uh
Nordic poetry well be wolf is actually
Pros isn't it be wolf and there is the
Eda Etc Germanic poetry I'm kind of
slightly I have some exposure to that um
I've seen some French poetry Etc Latin
also has poetry but yeah um so
Wordsworth William woodsworth had great
poems I remember when I when I was in
school I was struck by some of his
poetry U what was that Lucy a poem
called Lucy rather sad poem but yeah and
then um you have people like uh Sylvia
Plath ra rather tragic figure and uh
what was her husband's name the guy who
wrote about
crows so my point is
um I think everyone feels that their
culture and their literature is
superior uh but there may be some truth
to it so I'm not familiar with Arabic
poetry I I'm aware that they have lots
of poetry and all that probably good
poetry but uh Hindi poetry and and
Persian poetry Dari poetry I I it's
quite famous pan poetry has also
influenced Udu poetry in in India and we
obviously have a very ancient tradition
in the subcontinent of Sanskrit poetry
Sanskrit poetry can be incredible I mean
if you off the top of my head if you if
you listen to the Shiva tand Tanda stra
that's incredible the alliteration and
so on so
forth so yeah you will always feel that
your The Poetry in your mother tongue or
your your own cultural civilization
language is better but it may be perhaps
true when it comes to the subcontinent
that ours our poetry is is better Dari
is person but they are very closely
related related to
us it may be true that our poetry is
better I I kind of like Japanese poetry
as well they have very nice poetic forms
Haiku is brilliant I love
haikus uh so I'm kind of a person who
wants to experience Beauty across the
world I listen to music from across the
world I listen to music from Mali for
God's sakes Mali Mali is a western
African nation I listen to music from
everywhere in the
world but may be true that you know some
some music is better than other I mean I
always say right the Indian Raga music
Indian classical music there is no
comparison anywhere in the world with
what with that intellectual achievement
Indian
ragas uh so yeah at the end of the day
beauty is subjective beauty lies in the
eyes of the beholder but I kind of agree
with Imran over here that our poetry for
the subcontinent and Persia probably is
better than poetry from the West
okay India wins the subcontinent our
region
wins okay ad Guru Prasad says we know
Sanskrit was univ was the universal
language in Ancient India it was the
civilizational language the glue that
held our civilization together then how
come so many different languages
formed why did they form because we
don't see any linguistic diversity in
any other country or taking collectively
a geographical region well
are you sure about that so look I am
familiar for with for example France
okay so let's
uh let's
uh okay let me put that on the screen
let's look at Regional languages in
France for example France is not very
large
country okay let's put this on the
screen so if you look at a small nation
like France which is just a fraction of
India's
size how many languages do you have in
France
75 Regional languages in France
okay so languages like alashan Bas Bron
Catalan cor Franco o the long Etc let's
take a look at a map for example this is
a map linguistic map of France we have
so many languages
proval
ROM or Le
BR so there are languages that are Roman
languages Romans languages there are
languages that
are derived from the ancient Celtic
languages and so on you have the Flemish
language Flo in the north Kik alsas you
have Ona from the Ona
region and so much more so even a small
nation like France has so many languages
such linguistic diversity 75 languages
at least in
total okay so and I can show the same
thing for Italy Italy is a whole bunch
of
languages okay dialects and languages
and they have been subsumed or kind of
out shadowed by the official language
Italian italiy and in France also all
these little languages beautiful
linguistic diversity all of that has
been essentially suppressed by the main
language French the official language of
the nation so that is something you will
see everywhere in the world linguistic
diversity but nowhere will you see the
kind of linguistic diversity we have in
the subcontinent tremendous linguistic
diversity hundreds of languages
thousands of
dialects in the Indian subcontinent so
it's because we
are the second most diverse population
anywhere in the world outside of Africa
Africa has the most genetic diverse in
linguistic diversity in the whole world
but Africa is
gigantic
gigantic and outside of Africa it is
India that has that the second highest
genetic and linguistic diversity it's
because we are the oldest non-african
population the outof of Africa
migration the people who were part of
the original Out of Africa
migration they first settled in India in
the subcontinent and from there they
spread all across the world so the the
genetic lineages that we have in India
whether they are the matr lineal
lineages or patr lineages are the oldest
known African genetic lineages haplo
groups and similarly because of that we
will also have a tremendous linguistic
diversity in India so that's why we have
so many languages in India they just
form naturally the subcontinent is so
large we think of it as a small thing on
the map but it's an enormous piece of
geographical real estate
and there are mountains there are
valleys there are rivers there so much
and the population obviously get
separated over the thousands of
kilometers and that's how over centuries
they evolve differently differently in
from a linguistic sense from a from a
culinary sense and so on so forth and
people even start looking different over
centuries you know some people develop
fair skin some people develop darker
skin and so on so that's why there is so
much diversity in the subcontinent
because we are the oldest population we
are ethnically incredibly diverse
genetically incredibly diverse and yet
so
similar and that's why we have so many
languages rra sarar asks lots of
excellent questions if I if I take his
questions I can do at least 10 ask
abijit episodes so thank you so much
rudit for all the wonderful questions
you ask I'm going to take two or three
maybe today and I'll take a lot over
over the future episodes so uh this
question is some Indians always say that
English is very helpful to connect the
whole of India and help Indians to
receive higher education in life but
countries like China Japan Korea provide
higher studies to their people in their
respective native languages instead of
English or French yet their GDP
lifestyle and education is much higher
all of that is much higher and better
than that of India don't you think
Sanskrit should have could have done
this job better than English what's your
opinion on this I completely agree with
you look there is there is
this this debate in India which you come
across on a daily basis today I met
somebody with which with whom I had the
same
discussion and you will find that there
are lots of people in India especially
middle class Indians and upper middle
class Indians
who are in favor of English being the
official language of India and they
genuinely feel that English is something
that gives gives Indians a lot big
advantage over other nations and you
will find generally that this expr this
opinion is expressed among those Indians
who are good at English who speak
English quite well okay you won't find
this opinion among Indians from let's
say Tire two Tire three cities Indians
who struggle with this foreign language
unlike people who live in large cities
and people who have gone through the
English medium education
so the real question is is does English
provide some kind of advantage to to
India just because you speak English
because you speak because so many of you
speak English does it mean that you have
some
Advantage well if you go back a couple
of centuries French was the lingua fanka
of the world right uh French was the
number one language and you go back a
few centuries in the western world you
had Latin which was the language of the
h B and before that you had various
other languages when it comes to our
part of the world it was always Sanskrit
now the examples you have given are
extremely appropriate China there's no
English language education it hasn't
prevented China from becoming the second
largest economy in in the world Japan
has only Japanese language
education you will find very few
Japanese people speaking good English
they don't care they don't need that and
is the most technologically advanced
nation in the world and their lack of
English fluency doesn't prevent them
from doing well in in the world same for
Korea same for Germany same for the
Arabic Nations same for every other
nation in the world that has done well
it's only India that has this mental
colonization and this slavish adherance
to the English
language so my opinion is that yeah if
you know the language it it it kind of
eases your travel across the world world
because you have this familiarity with
this language and it's the international
language that is currently the the
hegemonic language in the world like
like Latin used to be during Roman Roman
times in the Western World so it it kind
of helps individuals see we have to
understand that if it helps an
individual it doesn't mean it helps the
country if I speak great English and I
travel across the world I'm going to
have a great time because everybody
everywhere the officials Etc the
passport the Visa officials passport
officials tourism professionals
Hospitality people Etc they all speak
English so I will not need to learn the
local language as long as I know English
so it's great for me as a traveler as a
tourist as a business person or whatever
right but for a
nation it it hampers the nation in the
long run because it it uh creates this
sense of
inferiority as a nation as as a
collective you know this sense of
national inferiority that we have to
depend on a foreign language and it's
not even something you think about
consciously it's subconscious it's
simply subconscious so overall it it
creates a slavem minded population a
population with a collective inferiority
complex and that's what we have in India
Indians have a big big inferiority
complex most Indians do
so I've always been a proponent of
Sanskrit Sanskrit is the only language
that deserves to be the civilizational
language of India and there are lots of
people because of the education system
who have been brainwashed into hating
this but that's the only way India will
rise to Greatness Again by embracing
re-embracing Our civilizational Heritage
and the only civilization language the
only language can be that can be a
civilization language in India and
someday worldwide why not why not it's a
it's a superior language way Superior to
English or any other language I can
think
of okay some comments from pashon people
okay so I have this uh video clip about
pashun other pashun Turks Iranians or
Indians from episode 35 of asab okay so
there are two comments here from pashon
people
uh first the first comment says as a
pashon historian I agree with you we
pashun were mostly Hindus or Buddhists
the kandahari dance is very close to the
Gujarati Garba the katak attend dance is
very close to rajput dance so that's
what a pashon historian says now below
that there's this other question there's
other comment from another pashon person
which says that as a pashon you are 100%
wrong we have zero DNA similarities with
Indian people we are not indians we were
a nomadic group in the past and we are
Eastern iranic group and I sure I can
dig up comments in which some pashon
people claim that they are of Jewish
origin so that is this is what foreign
occupation has done to Afghanistan to
the pan people they don't even know who
they are anymore look I have shown this
in the past on this asab show I have
shown it multiple times the genetic
evidence demonstrates that the pashun
are an extension of the northern Indian
population they are an extension of the
northern Indian demographics
ethnicity of course there is a bit of
foreign component because Afghanistan
has is kind of at the crossroads of
traveling of travel between east and
west and so on so forth It's been
invaded lots of times by the Turks by
the various various uh various Powers so
there is a foreign component for sure
there is a turkey component in the pan
population a little bit but overall it's
still part of the extended Northern
Indian uh
population and there is zero uh
Jewish uh DNA among the pashon there is
a little bit of turkic DNA and when it
comes to the Iranian iranic population
look the Iranians and the Indians are
essentially part of the same ethnic
group you go back a few thousand years
it's it's the same ethnic group the only
two genuinely Arian nations are India
and Persia no other ethnic group can
claim to be Arian okay only the Indians
and the Iranians have the right to call
themselves
Arians and obviously the pashun are part
of that they are an let's say in they're
not even Indo Iranian they're actually
an indic ethnic group but uh look you
can't convince people who don't want to
be convinced if if people are open to
absorbing new information and taking it
seriously and thinking critically then
you can convince them with facts and
data but if someone doesn't want to
believe is is not willing to listen to
to new information and and take it
seriously there's nothing you can do to
convince them so that's just Where We
Are
Okay g Deva 2002 says tell us about the
character of popes in medieval Europe
how did the Pope rule Catholic Europe in
medieval times before the Protestant
Reformation for example did the then
so-called monarch of let's say England
obey the pope loyally and was
essentially a vasal what happened if so
if some so-called Monarch tried to
disobey and I've heard that despite the
official requirement of the Pope being
celibate many popes had illegitimate
children multiple women women including
sex slaves isn't it hypocritical that
many popes had illegitimate children
while forcing the lower Catholic priests
to and monks to remain celibate okay big
big big question and I'll try and answer
in in in brief concisely look popes were
the most powerful human beings in Europe
essentially okay for the longest time
and they there was you can look at up
there were many popes who had armies of
their own and they essentially you are
right monarchs of England and various
other parts of Europe where essentially
there was Sals and the popes could if if
someone rose up against the pope or or
against the church or or or try to
disobey the church then they could be
excommunicated and they the popes could
the church could have other kingdoms and
and and uh other kingdoms and Kings
essentially attack that nation and
destroy it and and remove that guy from
Power the guy who disobeyed and
installed somebody else in power it's
happened and uh for for example England
so nobody dared to do that but the Henry
VII I believe it was who wanted to marry
who wanted to divorce uh Katherine of
Aragon and he wanted to marry an bolain
and he needed the paper dispensation to
go ahead with the with the divorce and
the pope didn't want to was unwilling to
give
permission to divorce Katherine of
Aragon so what Henry the8 did was the
was because he was safe on his Island in
England he essentially uh started a new
church and the Anglican Church okay and
he divorced his wife and married an
bolain who became the mother of the next
Queen of England and Katherine was
no Katherine of Aragon was the mother of
the next Queen of England and the one
after that was the daughter of anolin
and so on uh so generally if somebody
disobeyed the church they were destroyed
uh all monarchs in Europe were vasal of
the church that is correct uh what about
popes being celebrated
Etc okay let's let's uh let me
um um let me find some
article okay let me put this Wikipedia
article on the screen I've always I've I
I maintain this that Wikipedia is not a
reliable source of India when it comes
to Indian reliable source of information
when it comes to Indian history
especially but let's put this Wikipedia
article on the
screen check this out list of sexually
active for
okay St Peter he had
Offspring Felix uh a whole bunch of
people okay fathered illegitimate
children before holy orders before holy
orders before they became holy
essentially then known to or suspected
of having fathered illegit with children
after receiving holy orders a reasonably
big list of
popes not married not married who he had
a mistress not married affair with magd
Magdalen F not married
then relationships with women a bunch of
popes had relations with women while
being the
pope uh during the pontificate
relationships with men as well so there
you have it
okay uh relationships with women as well
as men Benedict the 9th apparently
very well um what can I say interesting
person so look that's Wikipedia okay
that's not me making claims that's
that's the official Wikipedia page and
there you can look up look up the page
and look you know check out all the
resources they've given all the
references and it's clear that this was
this was a
case so is this hypocrisy uh look I
don't know what to call it but it is
what it is and today it is alleged that
most of the clergy in the Vatican are
essentially homosexuals male
that's what is alleged I don't know if
it's true or not but there's
documentaries in books written about
that okay there are books that have been
written about this there are
documentaries that have been made about
this so it's not me making the claims go
and check it out yourself Google is your
best friend learn how to do a Google
search a basic Google search you'll find
all the information you need next
question rodra sarar says we know that
many Indians went to Southeast Asia and
became Kings yes southeast Asia Su aomi
Laos all that all of that but did any
Indians manage to do the same in the
west and in Central Asia look there are
lots of uh Records in the Vic from the
in vic literature of Indians migrating
westwards and it is known that there
were many Indian origin Kingdoms in
Central Asia where today you have
kazakistan Tajikistan usbekistan all all
of that okay the Central Asian
region um so you had many Indian origin
Kingdoms in in in this region U
you there still are ruined temples Etc
in this region but most of them have
disappeared because they have been
converted into worship places of a
different
religion there were even a bunch of
Hindu temples in uh in
Armenia which were destroyed 2,000 years
ago and churches were built in their
place and today those churches are gone
there are
mosques mosques there but now it is no
longer Armenian it is now aeran it is
aarani held territory and so on a very
complicated thing so you had Indian
origin kingdoms all across Central
Asia and the skians were of Indian
origin they obviously mixed with various
other ethnicities and they became almost
unrecognizable but there was a skan
invasion of India about 2,000 years
before today roughly which gave rise to
the skan kingdoms of the northern
satrapas and the Western chatra the
mahak chatas and they conquered those
parts of India
and assimilated harmoniously into the
Indian population they were not
foreigners they the same cultures in
very similar languages and so on and
obviously then you you also have the the
the mitani the mitani kingdom in present
day Anatolia Syria Etc their Capital was
vukani the mine of great wealth in
Sanskrit their aristocracy their
nobility the ruling class spoke Vic
Sanskrit late Vic Sanskrit they were of
Indian origin there is an entire horse
training manual written in the huran
language that was authored by a guy
called Kuli and that guy did not well
the hurrian language was incapable of
transmitting certain technical
information because that those words did
not exist in the hurian language so he
was forced to resort to writing those
terms in his native language which was
Sanskrit so um you had Indian origin
kingdoms and kings and dynasties in
Central Asia Western Asia Etc it's well
known right next Priyanka says is it
true that the US Russia and China have
nearly 11,000 7,000 5,000 satellites
respectively orbiting the Earth how
significant is this of a threat to
India okay good interesting question
let's let's go to
statista uh number of satellites number
of
satellites in orbit
oh let me put that on the screen so how
many satellites does each does the do
the major Nations have in
orbit so this is figures from up to as
of April 30 2022 the US has as of 2022
they had 3,433 satellites the Chinese
had
541 Russia 172 and the rest of the world
1319 I'm not sure if this is active
satellites or what but okay this is what
statista says it's a reasonably reliable
source of
information what else do we have uh
number of satellites launched by Year
from 57 to
2019 so you can see each year how many
satellites were launched and you can add
it up to get a reasonable idea of how
many satellites have been launched until
now
cumulatively um number of satellites in
orbit we saw that what about this
government expenditure on space programs
22 and 23 by Major country the US has
obviously the what is this okay 22 is
light blue 23 is black or dark blue so
the us obviously has the largest
expenditure
billion China is next with4 billion
dollar Japan 4.65 France
3.47 Russia 3.41 billion the EU
2.81 Germany $2.29 billion the small
small nation of Italy has a budget of 2
expenditure of $ 2.11 billion and then
you have India $ 1.69 billion so as you
can see the the the nation of India the
government of India has almost no
ambition when it comes to the India's
space
capabilities so uh going back to
satellites
um so from from what this website tells
us the US has about 3.4 th000 satellites
in orbit the Chinese of 541
Russians
172 um but maybe the figure of the total
number of satellites they've launched
this far may be much
higher uh so how significant of a threat
is this to a nation like India I
wondered how many satellites India has
in total
orbiting uh the planet maybe less than
100 how many of these are active maybe
less than 30 40 maybe about 50 I'm not
sure okay not sure about that I'm sure
if I do some research right now I can
dig it up but then I have to keep quiet
and do some silent work which I don't
want to do so um obviously if you don't
have sufficient Assets in space and
other nations have especially your major
rival China and the global superpower of
the US then it obviously poses a threat
to you it we may not understand it we
may not comprehend that this can pose a
threat but it's a threat you could
deploy weapons on satellites there are
lot lot of satellites that are launched
that that are essentially military
satellites some of them have remote
sensing capabilities what we call spy
satellites and some of them may have
weapons of various kinds that we may not
be aware of okay these space launches
happen and they don't publicize what's
being launched up there so the Chinese
may have various kinds of weapons
Weaponry in orbit some of them may be
targeted maybe targeting India the
Americans may have some of that stuff
the Americans have all kinds of uh
technological advancements that we may
not be aware of so yeah it definitely
pauses a threat to India so I I've said
this so many times India needs to be
ambitious when it comes to the comes to
the space program we need to I don't
know how many space launches we have
every year maybe 10 maybe less than 10
extremely unambitious space program we
have some of the best
you know rocket engineers and space
engineers in the world what you call
Rocket scientists we have some of the
best in the world but we not leveraging
the talent so yeah I mean look
at we we are not even trying to develop
reusable rocket technology I don't know
what we are doing very uh disappointing
State of Affairs
overall Malik said says will the US be
an indispensable
Empire um if they achieve interplanetary
travel before any other Nation or
something in Quantum Computing related
or something we can't think of we know
Empires rise and fall but that's the
case only related to Conquest on Earth
if hypothetical hypothetically the US
achieves would have stated above will
their empire be immortal the second
question is America shocked the world in
World War II by showing nuclear weapons
which are only created by them so is
there any chance that they now have a
weapon which the world doesn't know or
is is completely
secret so will the US become
undefeatable
indomitable unvanquishable if they
achieve interplanetary travel or some
major advance in Quantum Computing AI
whatsoever obvious obviously absolutely
look Empires are built with
technology at any given point in time in
past
history the most powerful kingdoms and
empires in the world world were the ones
with the best
technology okay not the not the most not
the most ferocious men or not the most
not the bravest men it's always about
technology the best technology so today
the US is the best technology the
Chinese are trying the best to catch up
with the US India doesn't have any
Ambitions
whatsoever um so I my point is what's
India doing about AI where is India's
AI um Endeavor what about Quantum
Computing is India even trying to
develop a quantum computer a
superposition of cubits that can be
sustained I don't think so so India
doesn't seem to have any Ambitions at
all um but the US is
obviously uh way ahead of everybody else
so if they achieve a significant
technological breakthrough like
interplanetary travel U colonizing the
moon colonizing Mars Etc it could make
them essentially undefeatable
until well nothing lasts forever
obviously maybe they may last their
empire May last another Century or two
it may happen or Quantum Computing or AI
whatever so yeah that that that I agree
with you that's right it won't become
immortal but it will last another couple
of centuries at least um the second
question is in World War II they
developed nuclear weapons no one had
that no one knew about that so is it
possible the Americans have some weapon
or some technology like that which no
one knows about today and nobody else
has it's very possible of course it's
possible it's possible that they have
have they may have
achieved artificial super intelligence
by now and they would obviously not let
the world know about
it so look there's artificial
intelligence which we are all aware of
you know chat gbt all that stuff you
know chat Bots that's AI then there is
Agi artificial general intelligence
which is an AI that can genuinely think
which may actually even be conscious and
which may have humanik IQ IQ of between
135 and 150 that's intelligent human
beings right a person who has an IQ of
135 is is on the higher range of the
spectrum of human IQ if you are 150 160
you are genius level um so that is
artificial general intelligence roughly
equivalent to human IQ 135 130
135 but ASI artificial super
intelligence it it represents something
like IQ
human equivalent IQ of maybe 350 or 500
it's Way Beyond human capabilities okay
and that may totally revolutionalize the
world it may give rise to technology
that we can't perhaps even imagine
Technologies like maybe creating
artificial worm holes traveling to other
galaxies maybe time travel all of that
stuff that is essentially science
fiction fiction and fantasy
so ASI artificial super intelligence
whoever achieves that may be able to
grasp those technology and create those
Technologies and if somebody does that
they will not let the world know about
it so it's possible that ASI may already
exist and the Americans may have become
undefeatable it's possible very much
possible uh rod rodit sarar says why did
Sark fail but asan on the other hand
serves served its purpose Sark is what
is the full form of sarc South Asian
Association of for regional Co operation
SAR it's a subcontinental organization
and Assan is the association of
Southeast Asian Nations these are both
economic cooperation blocks
organizations so asan succeeded and Sark
has failed there are no Sark Summits
anymore s there's no activity in Sark
anymore so Sark has failed but asan is
doing well why is that so it's because
there is no Pakistan in Southeast Asia
there is no Pakistan like nation that
hates all of its neighbor and exports
terrorism there is no such nation in
Southeast Asia that's why asan has
succeeded they're all cooperating with
each other in various ways obviously as
neighbors you will have certain theves
and all that which which happens with
all neighbors but overall there is no
such Nation like Pakistan over there a
nation that is their own but their enemy
and an exporter of terrorism in
subcontinent we have unfortunately
Pakistan okay I have nothing personal
against the people of
Pakistan but as a nation it's an
exporter of terrorism and
so that's why India has given up on Sark
Mr Modi has finally said enough of Sark
we don't need to do this we will
cooperate with various nations in the
subcontinent on a one toone basis or on
a bilateral on a bilateral or trilateral
basis but we don't need to do it through
through the mechanism of SAR because it
involves Pakistan and where Pakistan
exists there problems so that's why Sark
has been essentially abandoned by India
if India abandon sark then there's no
point of Sark existing anymore so that's
what's happened asan there's no Pakistan
there that's why it has
succeeded dungar Singh Chan says how to
deal with health anxiety according to
modern science even if you maintain a
good lifestyle you still cannot prevent
horrendous diseases like neurological
diseases cancers Etc how do you deal
with
this how do I deal with this or how does
anyone deal with this first of all you
do what you can you live a good
lifestyle you exercise regularly you get
sufficient sunlight every day there a
few 15 20 minutes half an hour at least
of sun sunlight exposure every day uh
you eat a good diet you don't overeat
you don't you don't undereat you don't
do anything stupid like drinking too
much or or whatever do drink drugs or
whatever you can imagine don't do any of
those stupid things those silly things
do the best you can to have a you know
to to have good health that's the first
thing you can do so do what you can
what's what's
within your grasp secondly whatever the
factors that you can't control don't
think about them don't worry about them
there's nothing you can do about them
okay that's how you deal with health
health anxiety what is anxiety anxiety
comes from
worry and anxiety comes from worrying
about things you can't
control but what's the point of thinking
about things you can't control when you
can't control them it's beyond your
control give it up whatever you can
control do your best to do your best at
it but the things you can't control
what's the point of dwelling on those
things that is beyond you right so
that's how you deal with health
anxiety that's all don't worry about
things you can't control don't think
about them what's the point be happy
enjoy that's what I would say okay I'm
done with the questions for today let's
take a few questions from the live
chat okay uh uh let's Okay so I am now
looking at the live chat if you have
questions please ask me now I'll take a
few of
these okay there is a question by Shivan
how to develop soft skills how to read
personality and make friends based on
that guest to thrive and come on top in
specific domains like medical sciences
and
Entrepreneurship how to read a
personalities look I don't know if there
is any hard and fast way method or set
of technique to for reading
personalities I would say go out there
and meet as many people as possible the
more exposure you have to various kinds
of people the better you get at
understanding what kind of person you
have you you have come
across so it's all about meeting lots of
people the more people you meet the more
familiar you get with various types of
people that's what I would say I don't
know about how to read personalities as
as a as a skill or as a skill set or as
a as set of techniques I don't know
about that but go out there and meet
lots and lots of people that makes you
really good at at reading personality I
would say and then you can make friends
based on
what's the kind of personalities that
that gel with you right and if you make
lots of friends you will thrive in
whatever domain you're in medical
Sciences entrepreneurship especially
entrepreneurship where you need to have
good friends and good partners good good
business partners and all that yeah you
need that so you need to be able to read
personalities and and and judge people
well so yeah yeah meet lots and lots of
people from various walks of life that's
the way to do
it right
okay jph ped says I believe the Western
world is built upon misogyny and female
hatred the Western world is going to
collapse and lose Global hegemony the
West is awful and barbaric okay um well
historically there's been definitely
some some or more than some of that
but not sure if it's going to
collapse the Western world is in you
mean Western culture Etc it may it may
disappear based on the kind of
immigration that's happening um there
definitely is some of that over there
yeah
okay um Samar aara says how to catch an
explanation
quickly um if someone is is explaining
something how do you catch that quickly
even do you how do you grasp that how do
you understand that well um first of all
you need to pay
attention when someone's explaining
something you pay attention you shut
down your thought process and just pay
attention and focus and secondly it
helps to have some familiarity with the
subject that is being expounded upon
what the person is explaining and that's
what you do and then you go and do your
homework you maybe note down what was
said and then you go and study it on
your own
and try and build upon what was
explained that may take time obviously
but if you have a lot of experience
doing that you may be able to grasp it
quicker than
others
okay uh let's see what else do we have
okay dasan Singh says I until I don't
know about
veganism my life was going well but now
after knowing things I want to be a
vegetarian but then when I think about
the animal cruelty then the conflict
starts uh yeah cruelty animal cruelty
look it's a fish e fish fish eat fish
World our ancestors thousands no
millions of years ago were fish and then
we they they decided to come and crawl
out of out of the ocean and flop onto
the beaches of the world and then they
colonize the planet and they became
animals and Dinos SS and eventually
mammals and then from that humans came
after passing through a monkey phase ape
phase and the world is always about
animals eating animals or animals eating
plants plants are also living beings so
at the end of the day if you want to
survive you have to eat organic matter
whether it is plant matter or animal
matter now obviously you prefer to eat
plant matter then you don't have to kill
animals and all that but uh that is
simply the nature of the world you have
to kill something to eat plants are also
living beings right they may not have a
nervous system and they may hopefully
not feel pain but you are ending a life
there you're eating all those
cells
um when it comes to veganism versus
vegetarianism veganism means you simply
esw all animal products which includes
meat um milk eggs all of that uh when it
comes to vegetarianism especially in the
Indian context we do consume vegetarians
do consume milk
and dairy products like like cheese
paner Etc right and obviously when it
comes to dairy products there is the the
milk it comes from cows obviously and
when there is industrial scale
production of dairy products there is
going to be cows that are chained in
place or or kept in those confined
places and essentially
exploited which is sad obviously it's
sad uh so then you can choose to become
a vegan in that case but then you will
have to face certain nut nutritional
challenges in you know in
in getting the sufficient amount of
various macronutrients especially
protein very hard to do that if you are
completely
vegan so it's it's a ethical and moral
dilemma most people prefer not to think
about it and just do just consume
whatever suits you best most people
prefer to think about it but if you are
thinking about it if it is a dilemma for
you then maybe you can try being vegan
and completely estwing even dairy
products let's see what else we
have shat says how did the Mongols
manage to conquer Russia when they were
many other Empires that failed to do so
like the Ottomans the French the Polish
the Japanese and the most powerful among
them thir Reich the Mongols were
especially
special uh you must have heard of the
the German uh tactic or strategy called
Blitz C lightning Warfare you have a
defensive fortifications and all that
and you simply punch through that to
momentum I mean you can look up what
Blitz cre is well the Mongols invented
Blitz cre and they understood chingis
the great Shri chingis Khan the great
warrior for peace he understood the role
of energy and momentum in
Warfare and he he mobilized his entire
nation you know how many Mongol soldiers
were there during chingis Khan's time
about about 100,000
soldiers you can fit that entire Mongol
Army the entire Mongolian military into
the Eden Garden
stadium and with that they conquered the
world it was just sheer strategic and
tactical Brilliance and obvious
leadership and Sh chis Khan had at his
disposal incredible generals someone
like subai subai bahadar sub the Valiant
that guy was incredible he conquered
Europe after the death of jingis Khan
for his sons for chingis Khan's Sons for
chingis Khan's son o so it was about all
about you know meritocracy about
identifying talent and ating Talent
giving Talent power at its disposal and
the most brilliant tactics and
strategies you can imagine and
Technology the Mongols adopted whatever
technology they could find if the
Chinese had something they would take
that and make it their own you know uh
chain mail
armor uh crossbows okay we'll take that
whatever technological innovations they
discovered they adopted those and all of
that so so that's how they were able to
forge the greatest Empire the world had
ever seen until
then uh and they did that without modern
telecommunications without modern
technology without anything that we have
today incredible that feat okay jingis
Khan he essentially owned half the world
at the time half the Known World
incredible feat of of
expansion and probably I would say the
greatest conqueror of all time okay okay
we are almost
done Shivan says please give a bookshelf
tour I've been following this channel
for the past two years I've been looking
forward to you to get your Insight of
your knowledge and pattern recognition
skill sources books I will do that I in
the process of uh re redoing my entire
place so I'll I'll do the bookshelf tour
soon soon the non-classified
books all right okay okay so
uh Costo thank you so much I really
appreciate that I I I appreciate all of
you all of you
okay NAD says I am distracted during my
studies please help me I am addicted to
YouTube and cannot control the addiction
yeah today you have the situation social
media is is a huge distraction not only
for students for adults also I know
people hello hi you watching I'm talking
but you social media
addiction what do you do about that you
need to find a purpose that is greater
than your addiction or and if it is out
of control delete the social media
delete those apps from your phone or
wherever but U look if you have a
purpose that that genuinely drives you
motivates you then no addiction can can
withstand
that so how do you find that motivation
to study you have to think of where you
want to be in the future where do you
want to be in 10 years time 20 years
time five years time paint a brilliant
Vivid picture and paint a picture of
success and
then then you have to uh work back from
the success reverse engineer that okay
in five years time I'm going to be here
today I'm here how do I get there then
create that road map and then work on it
and if you can motivate yourself
sufficiently you will
not care about social media YouTube Etc
but I know it's it's a huge challenge
it's easier than done it sounds very
easy when I say it like when I speak I
know it's not that easy addictions are
are tough but yeah at the end of the day
the most important factor in in
defeating an addiction whatever it is
the most important factor is your
willpower so look I I wish I could come
and personally help you out but all I
can do is give you this this these
guidelines so please go ahead do that
make something good of your life I wish
you the greatest success and and please
do well okay okay so rad all the best
all the best sir please do
well okay uh that's it uh we're done
with this this live stream thank you so
much for all your questions apologies to
those of you who are still asking
questions I know there are so many more
questions but I'm going to do as many of
these live streams as possible and we
will interact as much as possible and
maybe
more uh live chat Q&A sessions perhaps
in case you know that works for you so
yeah with with that said it I this this
is the end of today's live stream this
episode of askab thank you so much for
all your questions for your viewership I
really appreciate that and I will see
you in next week's live streams very
soon until then take care and as always
keep raising your standards keep aiming
for better thank you see you soon